Data can take on one of two forms.
It can be categorical,
meaning that it classifies as a variable into a specific category.
Gender is a great example of a categorical variable.
You either identify yourself as a male or female.
Sometimes you will hear data called qualitative.
Qualitative data is categorical data, just by a different name.
Or data can be numerical or quantitative.
In this case, the numbers have meaning.
Generally, larger numbers mean more of something.
Weight, height, temperature are examples of numerical variables.
Further, numerical variables can be discrete or continuous.
Discrete variables take on a specific value and
must be an integer.
The number of vehicles that you own, or the number of flights that you
took this year, are examples of discrete variables.
You can't have a part of a car, or take part of a flight.
Continuous variables can take on any value within a range.
Weight, temperature are continuous variables because something might
weigh a fraction of a pound or a kilo, or
temperature can be somewhere between two values on a scale.