Let's start at the beginning, statistics is the process of
collecting, organizing, and interpreting data.
Data consist of individuals and variables.
Individuals are the objects of interest in your study, in other
words, what you are collecting your information or data on.
They can be actual individuals or people, or they can be other objects
such as cities, animals, products, stocks, anything, really.
Variables are characteristics of those individuals or
the attributes that you are measuring, such as height, weight,
age, satisfaction with something or the population size of a city,
average income, median house price, and average temperature.
A great way to store your data is in a spreadsheet.
Data typically takes this form where the rows are individuals and
the columns are variables.
In this example, each row represents a survey respondent and each column,
a piece of information or data that was gathered about that respondent.