Okay in this lesson we're gonna discuss hierarchical data.
Now I'm not sure I can say that word right so just bear with me.
So hierarchical data is a way to organize data with multiple
one-to-many relationships.
The structure is based on the rule that one parent can have many
children, but a child can have only one parent.
So let's look at example.
We could look at food.
So we could look at ice cream, so that would be the parent.
And the children might be gelato ice cream, low fat ice cream,
high fat ice cream, or brands of ice cream.
Okay, we could look at cereals.
Okay, that would be the parent.
And the children would be bran, granola, oatmeal.
There could be other things there.
And fruit could be the parent.
We might have apple, pears, plums and grapes.
Another example, we could look at enrollments in a college.
So we could look at HPER, the School of Health,
Physical Education and Recreation, okay, that would be the parent.
And then the children would be basically students
enrolled in public health, kinesiology or parks administration.
We might have the College of Arts and Sciences,
that would be the parent.
The children, and I'm not being exhaustive here,
would be basically students enrolled in sociology,
chemistry, mathematics, English, history or psychology.
We might have business school being the parent.
And we might have the children being basically
students enrolled in accounting, finance, marketing, and operations.
So we can learn in the next videos how we can
use two new exciting charts from Excel 2016, the tree map and
the sunburst charts, to summarize hierarchical data.