In this video, we're gonna show you how to install the Analysis ToolPak
add-in which is useful for a lot of calculations and statistics.
So you may already have this installed.
If you go to the data tab and you see Analysis ToolPak on the right or
Data Analysis add-in, you've got it.
Now, I uninstalled mine so I can show you how to install.
So all you do is you go to file, you go to options, you go to add-ins.
Now, don't click on Analysis ToolPak up here,
a lot of people make that mistake, you click go.
And now there's two Analysis ToolPak add-ins here,
Analysis ToolPak, Analysis ToolPak- VBA.
Don't worry about the VBA, just check Analysis ToolPak, click OK,
now if I go to data, you'll see Data Analysis and that's what we need.
Now, what happens to my students a lot is they've done this procedure
perfectly and it happens to me, and the Data Analysis add-in disappears.
Even though it's checked when you go add-ins.
Then what should you do?
You should uncheck it, okay, and
then reinstall it, that always seems to work and I have no clue why.
So in the next video,
we'll use this Data Analysis add-in to get descriptive statistics for
GM and Cisco monthly stock returns in the 1990s.