Now, let's learn how to create an actual box plot and interpret it.
So, let's go back to that draft lottery data.
So, in column A, we have the month, January through December of course,
and in column B, we have the number which the date was picked.
So, January 1st was picked 305th.
December 31st was picked a 100th, December 30th was picked third.
So, how can we summarize this data by month?
Well, we select the data in red, CTRL + SHIFT right arrow,
down arrow, and then we go Insert and then we'll get box and
whisker plot right here.
And, I'm just gonna click on the design tab and make this be black,
I think it looks better.
Okay, you can see things better.
Now, there's a definite downward trend here in the ends of the year.
You can see October, November, December,
you can see that the line here connecting the medians drops down.
And so, basically, that indicates that the months later in the year
seem to have, on the average, lower draft numbers which meant you were
more likely to go to Vietnam and, unfortunately, die.
Okay, and so, basically, statisticians concluded there wasn't
sort of adequate mixing of the capsules, that, basically,
the ones that were put in last were more likely to be picked first.
Now in 1971, they changed the mixing procedure, and
in a homework problem, you'll do the box plot for the 1971 draft lottery,
and you'll see that this pattern at the end of the year did not exist.
And in our next video,
we'll do another box plot, going back to our Cisco and GM data, and
showing how we can easily compare Cisco and GM with a box plot.
Probably much easier to do that than use the descriptive statistics or
the histograms that we used earlier.