In this video we're gonna learn how to graphically describe categorical
ordinal data.
So let's start with numerical data and try and put some categories in.
So we have the age of people that live in your town.
So how many people do we have?
5,000 people.
And so we might wanna break this up in to categories,
0-9 years old, 10-19, 20-29, 80-90.
Pivot table makes this a snap.
So select the data, including the heading.
Go insert, pivot table.
And we'll put this in the existing worksheet.
And then we'll pick age here.
Now, we want to count how many people in each age group.
We've got to be careful here.
See, it says, sum of age.
Excel was thinking you want to add these up. Okay.
So, like, for
six year olds, they add up to 300.
That means there's 50 six year olds.
But if you double click here, you can change this to count.
So now there's 50 six year olds.
But still, we want to put categories in there.
We want to group those ages.
So if you right click here, you can do group.
You can do ten year increments.
Zero through 90 in ten year increments.
See now we could graph this to get an idea of
basically the age distribution.
We could do percentages but we'll just leave it like this.
So we would do insert.
Okay, so we analyze.
And then basically Pivot Chart again.
And that column chart is absolutely fine.
And so now we've summarized our categorical ordinal data.
You can see there's a numerical order here.
The 90 year olds are older than the 0 to the nine year olds.
We can see the most common age group was baby bloomers, 50 to 59.
Now in the next video we'll show you an important way to summarize
categorical data known as cross tabs.