So another way to summarize hierarchical data
is a sunburst chart.
And it's got some advantages and
some disadvantages over the treemap chart, as we'll see.
So we can select our data for the bookstore again.
And all we gotta do is insert, go to right here, and
instead of selecting Treemap, Sunburst.
Okay, you can see it sorta looks like the sun there.
Okay, the disadvantage is you can't really, I think the human eye,
really spot what fraction of the area goes with each product.
The rectangles are easier I think for us to work with as human beings.
But the advantage here, you can see here H three through five,
I've got the breakdown of how the books went on the age three through
five kids, okay?
And I did not have that breakdown when I did the treemap chart.
But that's really all there is to sunburst charts.
You have to experiment with the right size, but
basically you can really see the hierarchical relationship better,
I think, in this case.
But you really, I don't think, can judge.
You can see the children's books for the highest percentage in the mag
and science fantasy, fiction fantasy, and do that well.
But I think with the rectangles,
it's easier to see the particular percentage there.
Now again, hovering over a particular point,
shows you the numerical value there.
So, in our next lesson, we're going to talk about Pareto charts,
which are really nicely done in Excel 2016.
So, we'll get to that in a few minutes