A histogram is a fancy bar chart.
The difference between a histogram and
a bar chart is that histograms show bars for
ranges of numbers, rather than for a single value as most bar charts do.
In addition, histograms are used to display continuous data,
whereas bar charts are used to display discreet data.
As a result, the bars in histograms touch, but
they do not touch on bar charts.
To construct a histogram, the first step is to bin the range of values,
that is, divide the entire range of values into a series of intervals.
And then count how many values fall into each of your intervals.
The bins are consecutive,
non-overlapping intervals of values associated with a variable.
The bins must be adjacent and are often, but
not required to be, of equal size.
In this case, we are summarizing the number of widgets sold each day for
two months.
We created bins the size of 20.
Histograms, like bar charts, are valuable tools, because they allow
us to better understand the shape or distribution of our data.
In general, we want our data to be normally distributed,
meaning it's symmetrical.
When it's not,
it's skewed, with data clustered at one end or the other.
As data analysis, symmetrical, or normally distributed data,
is not only pleasing to the eye, but to our spirits as well.
Because many statistical analyses assume normality of data.
In other words, if your data aren't normally distributed, you won't be
able to make the correct interpretation of your results.