In this lesson, we're gonna talk about the Pareto principle,
also known as the 80/20 rule, the law of the vital few, or
the principle of factor sparsity.
Basically, the Pareto principle states that for
many events, roughly 80% of the effects come from 20% of the causes.
So, here's some examples.
20% of the customers generate 80% of the profit.
20% of the products may generate 80% of the profit.
Most importantly, 20% of the people have 80% of the money.
And very interesting in today's internet age,
20% of the websites seem to get 80% of the hits.
And there's actually a mathematical explanation for that last point.
I'm not sure there is for the others.
So, how can we illustrate the Pareto principle or the 80/20 rule?
We can create Pareto charts using Excel 2016.
And a Pareto chart, named after the economist Pareto,
is a type of chart that contains both bars and a line graph.
So the individual values of your data are represented in descending
order by bars, and the cumulative total is represented by a line.
And so, in the next video,
we'll start teaching you how to make your own Pareto charts.